Thomas Wood Stevens papers, 1895-1984 (bulk 1897-1937)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series VI: Published Works and Manuscripts, 1896-1984
  - Blue Sky Press, 1899-1928
    - Milton, John, L'Allegro & Il Penseroso. 1902 (Box 50)
      Number 7 of 100 copies printed.
    - Blanden, Charles G., A Harvest of Reeds. 1902 (Box 50)
      Number 8 of 150 copies printed.
    - Burton, Charles Pierce, The Bashful Man, and Others. 1902 (Box 50)
      Number 7 of 500 copies printed.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood and Noble, Alden Charles, The Morning Road. 1902 (Box 50)
      Number 38 of 200 copies printed on paper, 15 additional copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Poe, Edgar Allen, The Fall of the House of Usher. 1903 (Box 50)
      Number 69 of 150 copies printed on paper, 15 additional copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Cheney, C. Emma, Mistress Allice Jocelyn: Her Letters. 1903 (Box 50)
      Number 399 of 500 copies printed on paper, number 17 of 20 copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Blanden, Charles G., The Unremembered God and other Poems. 1903 (Box 50)
      Number 5 of 10 copies printed on Japan vellum, number 84 of 150 copies printed on paper.
    - Peattie, Elisa W., Castle, Knight and Troubadour. 1903 (Box 50)
      175 copies printed on paper and 25 copies on Japan vellum. This copy is not numbered.
    - Poe, Edgar Allen, The Cask of Amontillado. 1904 (Box 50)
      Numbers 31 and 56 of 300 copies printed on Van Gelder hand-made paper, number 10 of 15 copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Blanden, Charles G., The Battle of Love. 1904 (Box 50)
      300 copies printed on Van Gelder hand-made paper, 15 copies printed on Japan vellum. This copy is not numbered.
    - Goldsmith, Oliver, The Life of Richard Nash, Esquire. 1904 (Box 50)
      Number 37 of 100 copies printed on hand-made paper, 25 additional copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Le Gallienne, Richard, The Burial of Romeo and Juliet. 1904 (Box 50)
      Number 143 of 300 copies printed on hand-made paper, 25 additional copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood and Noble, Alden Charles, The Parchment in the Hollow Hilt. 1904 (Box 50)
      Numbers 30 and 159 of 225 copies printed on Italian hand-made paper, number 5 of 25 copies printed on Japan vellum. Additional copy unnumbered, inscribed to Louise McPherson by the authors.
    - Morris, William, Sir Galahad; A Christmas Mystery. 1904 (Box 50)
      Number 116 of 500 copies printed on paper, 25 additional copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Rossetti, Christina, Goblin Market. 1905 (Box 50)
      Number 4 of 15 copies printed on Japan vellum, 300 additional copies printed on Van Gelder hand-made paper, one copy, unnumbered.
    - Erskine, Payne, The Harper & the King's Horse. 1905 (Box 50)
      Unnumbered copy of 500 copies printed on Van Gelder hand-made paper, unnumbered copy of 25 copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - Crow, Martha Foote, The World Above. 1905 (Box 50)
      Number 182 of 500 copies printed on Van Gelder hand-made paper, 25 additional copies printed on Japan vellum.
    - The Pageant, a magazine of belles-lettres. 1905-1907 (Box 50)
      vol. 1, no. 1-7, June-December, 1905 (2 copies of no. 1, 5-7).
      vol. 2, no. 1-2, 6, May-June 1906, March 1907 (Also titled The Pageant Books).
  - Private Press Books, 1897-1927
    - Seymour, Ralph Fletcher, The Love Letters of Abelard and Heloise. Alderbrink, Chicago, Illinois. 1903 (Box 51)
      515 copies on paper, 12 on Japanese imperial parchment. This copy is paper.
    - Keats, John, The Eve of St. Agnes, Alderbrink, Chicago, Illinois. 1900 (Box 51)
      Number 341 of 800 copies on paper, 4 copies on parchment.
    - Hewlett, Maurice Henry, The Birth of Roland, Alderbrink, Chicago, Illinois. 1911 (Box 51)
      400 copies on paper, 10 on Japan vellum. This copy is printed no paper.
    - Peattie, Elia, W., The Angle with a Broom, Alderbrink, Chicago, Illinois. (Box 51)
      Number 415 of 700 copies printed.
    - McNeill, James Abbot, Mr. Whistler's "Ten O'clock", Alderbrink, Chicago, Illinois. 1907 (Box 51)
      300 copies printed.
    - Browning, Robert, The Pied Piper of Hamlin, Alwil Shop, Ridgewood, New Jersey. 1901 (Box 51)
    - Lord Byron, The Prisoner of Chillon, Alwil Shop, Ridgewood, New Jersey. 1900 (Box 51)
      Numbers 44 and 71 of 300 copies printed. Number 44 inscribed to Louise McPherson by Frank B. Rae, Jr.
    - Fowler, Egbert Willard, Dream Rest, Alwil Shop, Ridgewood, New Jersey. 1901 (Box 51)
      Number 3 of 100 copies printed. Additional copy, not numbered, issued as Alwil Brochure, Series I, no. 2.
    - Plato, The Apology of Socrates, Alwil Shop, Ridgewood, New Jersey. 1901 (Box 51)
      Number 140 of 475 copies printed on Van Gelder hand-made paper, 25 additional copies printed on imperial Japan vellum. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by Frank B. Rae, Jr.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood and Noble, Alden Charles, Hold Redmere, Alwil Shop, Ridgewood, New Jersey. 1901 (Box 51)
      Number 134 of 450 copies printed on hand-made paper, 50 additional copies on Japan vellum.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood, The Unsought Shrine, and Titian, The Boy, Alwil Shop, Ridgewood, New Jersey. 1901 (Box 51)
      Alwil Brochures, Series I, no. 1.
    - Yearbook, Brother of the Book, Chicago, Illinois. 1913 (Box 51)
    - Henry, Arthur, Peter and the Fairies, Brother of the Book, Chicago, Illinois. 1913 (Box 51)
    - Untitled, 1890-1942 (Box 51)
    - Pater, Walter Horatio, Duke Carl of Rosemold, Copland and Day, Boston, Massachusetts. 1897 (Box 51)
      500 copies printed.
    - Our Lady's Tumbler, Copland and Day, Boston, Massachusetts. 1898 (Box 51)
      A tale of Medieval France, translated into English from Old French by Isabel Butler.
    - Yeats, William Butler, Responsibilities, Cuala, Dundrum, Ireland. 1914 (Box 51)
      Number 347 of 400 copies printed.
    - Pope, Alexander, The Rape of the Lock, Elston, New Rochelle, New York. 1902 (Box 51)
      160 copies printed.
    - Noble, Alden Charles, The Buccaneer, Green Mountain, Brattleboro, Vermont. 1908 (Box 51)
      (3 copies) 150 copies printed.
    - Weitenkampf, Frank, The Etching of Contemporary Life, Dard Hunter, Marlborough-on-the-Hudson, New York. 1926 (Box 51)
      Imperfect, original etching by Ernest D. Roth lacking.
    - Bradley, William A., The Etching of Figures, Dard Hunter, Marlborough-on-the-Hudson, New York. 1901 (Box 51)
      Imperfect, original etching by William A. Levy lacking.
    - Havens, Munson Aldrich, Horace Walpole and the Strawberry Press, 1757-1789, Kirgate, Canton, Pennsylvania. 1901 (Box 51)
    - Garnet, Porter, A Documentary Account of the Beginnings of the Laboratory Press, Carnegie Institute of Technology, Laboratory Press, Carnegie Institute of Technology. 1927 (Box 52)
      160 copies printed on Lafuma-Navarre, 95 copies printed on Crown and Scepter. This copy is Lafuma-Navarre.
    - Brown, Bolton, Lithography, Merrymount, Boston, Massachusetts. 1923 (Box 52)
      Number 64 of 500 copies printed.
    - Lang, Andrew, Helen of Troy, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1987 (Box 52)
      Her life and translation done into rhyme from the Greek books. 925 copies printed.
    - Field, Michael (pseudonym), Underneath the Bough, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1898 (Box 52)
      925 copies printed.
    - Swinburne, Algernon Charles, The Heptalogia, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1898 (Box 52)
      450 copies printed.
    - Anodos, Fancy's Following, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1900 (Box 52)
      Anodos is a pseudonym for Mary Elizabeth Coleridge. 450 copies printed.
    - Rossetti, Daniel Gabriel, Hand and Soul, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1900 (Box 52)
    - Swinburne, Algernon Charles, Laus Veneris, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1900 (Box 52)
    - Hewlett, Maurice Henry, Quattrocentisteria, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1901 (Box 52)
      How Sandro Botticelli saw Simonetta in the Spring. 425 copies printed.
    - Schwob, Marcel, Mimes, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1901 (Box 52)
      500 copies printed. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by C. G. Blanden.
    - Aucassin and Nicolete, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1903 (Box 52)
      Translated to English by Andrew Lang.
    - Browning, Elizabeth Barrett, Sonnets from the Portuguese, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1903 (Box 52)
      With preface by Edmund Gosse.
    - Macleod, Fiona, Deirdre and the Sons of Usna, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1903 (Box 52)
      Fiona Macleod is a pseudonym of William Sharp. 925 copies printed.
    - Symons, Arthur, Lyrics, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1903 (Box 52)
      950 copies printed.
    - Browning, Robert, Pippa Passes, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1902 (Box 52)
    - Meredith, George, Modern Love, and other Poems, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1904 (Box 52)
    - Macleod, Fiona, From the Hills of Dream, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1904 (Box 52)
      Threnodies, songs and other poems. Fiona Macleod is a pseudym of William Sharp. 925 copies printed.
    - Schreiner, Olive, The Lost Joy, and Other Dreams, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1909 (Box 52)
    - Dowson, Ernest, The Pierrot of the Minute, Mosher, Portland, Maine. 1913 (Box 52)
      A dramatic fantasy in one act. 950 copies printed.
    - Browning, Elizabeth Barrett, Lord Walter's Wife, Philosopher, Wausau, Wisconsin. 1899 (Box 52)
    - Ellis, William, The Old Winconse, Philosopher, Wausau, Wisconsin. 1899 (Box 52)
    - Ellis, William, The Ketcham Pardon, Philosopher, Wausau, Wisconsin. 1900 (Box 52)
    - Crissey, Forrest, Olof and Yourself, Philosopher, Wausau, Wisconsin. 1897 (Box 52)
    - Gray, Thomas, Elegy Written in a Country Churchyard, Prairie, Chicago. 1905 (Box 52)
      100 copies printed.
    - The Basia of Joannes Secundus, Colonial, Boston, Massachusetts. 1901 (Box 53)
      Translated into English verse, to which is added the Epithalamium, with the English version of George Ogle, with a prefatory memoir by Wallace Rice. Number 206 of 365 copies printed upon Dutch hand-made paper, 26 additional copies on Japan vellum.
    - Guerin, Maurice de, The Centaur, Montague, Massachusetts. 1915 (Box 53)
      Translated by George B. Ives from French. Typography by Bruce Rogers. 135 copies printed.
    - Spenser, Edmund, Prothalamion: Epithalamion, Riverside Press of Houghton, Mifflin and Company. 1902 (Box 53)
      Typography by Bruce Rogers. 419 copies printed, 400 numbered and for sale. This copy no numbered, inscribed "Presentation copy" to Thomas Wood Stevens from Bruce Rogers?
    - Songs & Sonnets of Pierre de Ronsard, gentleman of Vendomois, Riverside Press of Houghton, Mifflin and Company. 1903 (Box 53)
      Selected and translated into English verse by Curtis Hidd Page, Typography by Bruce Rogers. Number 389 of 425 copies printed. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by Bruce Rogers.
    - Sidney, Sir Philip, Certaine Sonnets, Riverside Press of Houghton, Mifflin and Company. 1904 (Box 53)
      Typography by Bruce Rogers. Number 422 of 430 copies printed.
    - Wordsworth, William, IV Sonnets, Riverside Press of Houghton, Mifflin and Company. 1909 (Box 53)
      143 copies "Printed by Bruce Rogers for his friends, Christmas MDCCCCIX."
    - Schreiner, Olive, So Here Then Are Dreams, Roycroft, East Aurora, New York. 1901 (Box 53)
      Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by Elbert Hubbard.
    - Bacheller, Irving, The Story of a Passion, Roycroft, East Aurora, New York. 1899 (Box 53)
    - Beatty, John W., The Relation of Art to Nature, Rudge, William Edwin, New York. 1922 (Box 53)
      Typography by Bruce Rogers. 950 copies printed.
    - Morris, William and Walker, Emery, Printing, Village, Park Ridge, Illinois & Hingham, Massachusetts. 1903 (Box 53)
      Number 215 of 231 copies printed.
    - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, The Blessed Damozel, Village, Park Ridge, Illinois & Hingham, Massachusetts. 1903 (Box 53)
      110 copies printed.
    - Lamb, Charles, A Dissertation Upon a Roast Pig, Village, Park Ridge, Illinois & Hingham, Massachusetts. 1904 (Box 53)
      215 copies printed.
    - Browning, Robert, Rabbi Ben Ezra, Village, Park Ridge, Illinois & Hingham, Massachusetts. 1904 (Box 53)
      Number 12 of 173 copies printed.
    - Neale, Dr. John Mason, Good King Wenceslas, Village, Park Ridge, Illinois & Hingham, Massachusetts. 1904 (Box 53)
    - Morris, William, The Hollow Land, Village, Park Ridge, Illinois & Hingham, Massachusetts. 1905 (Box 53)
      220 copies printed.
    - Irving, Washington, Rip Van Winkle, Wayside, Springfield, Massachusetts. 1897 (Box 53)
      From the Sketchbook of Washington Irving.
  - Articles on the Theatre, Art, Printing, etc., 1899-1941
    Unless otherwise indicated, articles are authored by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - Bohemian Magazine. December 1908 (Box 54)
      p. 753, "Art in Chicago."
    - The Drama: A Quarterly Review. November 1914 (Box 54)
      p. 635, "A School of the Theatre Arts" (Carnegie Tech).
    - The English Journal. March 1937 (Box 54)
      p. 179, "How Good is Eugene O'Neill?"
    - The Fulcrum (Armour Institute of Technology). October-November, 1899 (Box 54)
      October, 1899, p. 15, "The Man at the Window."
      November, 1899, p. 23, "The Man at the Window."
    - Inland Printer. April 1902 (Box 54)
      p. 41, "Notes on the Pictorial Bookplate."
    - Inland Printer. February 1908 (Box 54)
      p. 355, "Art and the Printing Craft."
    - National Theatre Conference, Quarterly Bulletin. October 1939 (Box 54)
      p. 3, "One Yardstick."
    - The Play Book. April 1913 (Box 54)
      p. 21, "In Defense of Footlights."
    - The Play Book. May 1913 (Box 54)
      p. 3, "Robertson, a record."
    - The Play Book. June 1913 (Box 54)
      Issue devoted to the open-air theatre. Thomas Wood Stevens contributor and artist.
    - The Play Book. August 1913 (Box 54)
      p. 10, "A Festival of Northern Folklore."
    - The Play Book. August 1914 (Box 54)
      p. 16, "The Plan of a Laboratory Theatre" (Carnegie Theatre).
    - Proceedings of the Conference on the Drama in American Universities and Little Theatres, held at the Carnegie Institute of Technology, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. November 27-28, 1925 (Box 54)
      p. 77, "The Potentialities of a College Dramatic Department."
    - St. Louis Art League, Bulletin. May 1914 (Box 54)
      p. 19, "Note on an Open-air Theatre."
    - Saint Louis Review. March 15, 1932 (Box 54)
      p. 2, "The Audience in Search of a Theatre."
    - The School Arts Book. June 1912 (Box 54)
      p. 1003, "The Pageant as a School Exercise."
    - The School Arts Magazine. January 1913 (Box 54)
      p. 299, "The School is Beautiful-Mural Decorations by Art Students."
    - Bibliograhical Society of Chicago, Yearbook. 1900-1901 (Box 54)
      p. 25, "On Some American Bookmakers."
    - The Sketch Book. December 1905 (Box 54)
      p. 195, "Elements of Illustration."
    - Theatre Arts Monthly. January 1931 (Box 54)
      p. 59, "What the Audience Wants."
    - Theatre Arts Monthly September 1931 (Box 54)
      p. 729, "Field Notes on the War in Times Square."
    - Theatre Magazine. June 1918 (Box 54)
      p. 350, "A Non-commercial Theatre." (Carnegie Tech).
    - Books and Printing: "When the Author Prints." (Typescript). 1903 (Box 54)
    - Books and Printing: "An Open Letter to a Book-lover." (Typescript). 1905 (Box 54)
    - Books and Printing: "At the Sign of the Red Pale: William Caxton." April 1905 (Box 54)
      Published in Inland Printer.
    - Books and Printing: "The Birthplace of the Craft." October 1907 (Box 54)
      Extract from Inland Printer.
    - Books and Printing: "A Mail Course from Critics." (Typescript). ca. 1907 (Box 54)
    - Fine Arts: "Elements of Illustrations." (Typescript). 1906
    - Fine Arts: "Mural Paintings in the Sherman Park Assembly Hall." (Typescript). 1906-1910?
    - Fine Arts: "An Open Letter in the Matter of Translated Pictures." (Typescript). ca. 1910
    - Fine Arts: "The Artist's Efficiency." (Speech at Exhibitors' Dinner, Chicago Artists). January 31, 1911
    - Fine Arts: "Chicago and the Fine Arts." (Typescript). 1912
    - Fine Arts: "Art and Progress." (Typescript). 1913
    - Fine Arts: "A Note on the Provinces of Art Education." ca. 1910
      Extract from Educational Bi-Monthly.
    - Politics: "Stop! Look! and Listen!" (Typescript). (Box 54)
    - Politics: "Old Spanish Custom." (Typescript). (Box 54)
    - Travel I: "The Petrified Forest of Arizona." December 1902 (Box 54)
      Extract from The Garden of the Gods Magazine.
    - Travel I: "A Grand Canyon Bivouac." June 1902 (Box 54)
      Extract from The Independent.
    - Travel I: "Vababonds in Adobeland: San Domingo Days." 1902 (Box 54)
    - Travel II: "Vababonds in Adobeland: the Desert." (Typescript). 1902 (Box 54)
    - Travel II: "A Canyon Camp." (Typescript). 1907 (Box 54)
    - Theatre: Miscellaneous holographic notes. (Box 54)
      "Truism"
      "Education and the Art of the Theatre"
      "The Art of the Theatre"
      "To Rise Above Makeshift"
    - Theatre: "The Changing Theatre." (Holograph lecture notes). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Prospectus of a Plan for the Establishment of a Civic Theatre in Chicago." (Original draft and typescript). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Portrait of a Living Master." William Poel, (Typescript). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: A letter from Donald Robertson to Mr. N. H. Carpenter, Secretary, the Art Institute. March 20, 1909 (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "The Cranbrook Masque, Detroit." (Typescript). (Box 54)
      Accompanied by a letter to Mr. Weeks, July 12, 1916.
    - Theatre: The Field of the Dramatic Artist." Two versions. (Typescript). December 1922 (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Carnegie Tech: The First Phase." (Typescript). ca. 1915 (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "The Theatre Goes to School." (Typescript). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Pittsburgh's Unique Drama School." Radio talk. February 25, 1922 (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Education Aspect of the Drama." (Typescript). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Making the Play the Issue." (Typescript). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Art in School Pageants." (Box 54)
      Extract from an unknown source.
    - Theatre: "The Spoken Word in Pageantry." (Fragment). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "The Pageant as a School Exercise." (Typescript). (Box 54)
      Accompanied by a letter to Mr. Edwin O. Grover, President, Prang Company, January 6, 1912.
    - Theatre: "On Pageants." (Personal notes). (Box 54)
    - Theatre: "Re Quetzel's Bowl" (As done at the Cliff Dwellers Club). 1911 (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous: "New Fields for the Art Institute." (Box 54)
      Extract from Midland.
    - Miscellaneous: "An Appreciation of Donald Robertson." (Brochure). (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous: "Municipal Art League." (Memorandum of report of Committee on Plan of Work for the Ensuing Year). 1910 (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous: "The Making of a Dramatic Pageant." September 1912 (Box 54)
      Extract from Atlantic Education Journal.
    - Miscellaneous: "Mural Decorations by Art Students." January 1913 (Box 54)
      Published in The School Arts Magazine.
    - Miscellaneous: "A School of the Theatre Arts." 1914 (Box 54)
      Reprint from The Tartan, the student weekly of the Carnegie Institute of Technology.
    - Miscellaneous: "The Stage Without a Curtain." February 1938 (Box 54)
      Published in Theatre Arts.
    - Miscellaneous holograph notes form projected articles. (Box 54)
  - Stories (manuscripts in publications), 1901-ca. 1930
    Unless otherwise indicated, stories are authored by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - All-Story Magazine. September 1908 (Box 55)
      p. 99, "The Hidden Channel." By Michael Kinmarck.
    - All-Story Magazine. March 1910 (Box 55)
      p. 399, "Dyke Shannon, Gentleman."
    - The Bohemian. February 1901 (Box 55)
      p. 1, "As Happens for Unrest." With Alden Charles Noble.
    - The Western Trail. July, August, October, November 1903 (Box 55)
      Four issues containing a serial story by Thomas Wood Stevens, "The Story of the Oklahoma Farm."
    - Stories, (typescripts, some accompanied by original draft). ca. 1930 (Box 55)
      "Off the Straight and Narrow"
      "Believe it or Flop"
      "The Hickey"
      "One Star to Another"
      "Solo Flight"
      "The Great Line"
      "Damned to Beauty"
    - Stories, (typescripts). 1901-1910 (Box 55)
      "The Rumor and the Cross," ca. 1901
      "The Flight of Padre Moris, " 1902
      "The Maid of Domremi," 1903
      "Javalo Mowbray, Buccaneer," ca. 1903
      "A Buccaneer's Love," 1905
      "The Adventure of Nicholas Ford," 1905
      "The Helmeted Lady," 1906
      "The Truth About Hinbad," ca. 1906
      "Love and the Rolling Stone," 1907
      "Mr. Windever's Midnight Adventure," 1907
      "The Evolution of an Angler," 1905
      "Covert Agents," 1910
    - Stories, (extracts from magazines, some with drafts). 1900-1908 (Box 55)
      "A Letter in Gold," Phi Kappa Sigma Quarterly, 1900, with Alden C. Noble
      "Whom Slender Hands Betray," Criterion, October 1902
      "The Desperate Hunting," Criterion, 1904
      "Our Colonial Room," House Beautiful, January 1904
      "The Lesser Tragedy," Metropolitan prize story, February 1905 (Earlier versions: "Buccaneer's Love," "Spanish Main"
      "MacSkimming, the Thespian," Lippincott's, March 1905
      "King Arthur in Michigan," Reader, November 1906
      "The Letters of Life and Death," Cosmopolitan, October 1906
      "The King's Astrologer," Woman, November 1906 (Written in 1900 with Alden C. Noble, published under Stevens' pseudonym, Michael Kinmarck)
      "The Beating Wings," Midland, April 1908
    - Story Scenarios, fragments, etc. (holograph and typescript). (Box 55)
    - Essays by Thomas Wood Stevens and Alden C. Noble, (typescripts). 1901 (Box 55)
    - "Four Rides of Juan Gallego," (original draft and unfinished long version). (Box 55a)
  - Poems (manuscripts), 1900-1984
    Unless otherwise indicated, poems are authored by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - Early Poems. 1902-1921 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Poems. 1900-1937 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - The Pilot's Interlude, a play in four voices. No Date (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Two personal poems (Box 56, Folder 4)
      To Louise (McPherson)
      To Bertha (Jacques?)
    - Dark Discipline. 1938 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      Also known as Desert Processional and Desert Vigil. Published in Theatre Arts, 1939.
    - Westward Under Vega, a novel in verse. 1938 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Published by Covicci Friede.
    - The Cactus, a heroic ballad. 1940 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - The Gold Masks, sequel to Desert Processional. (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Video tape of Dark Discipline, Instruction Media of the University of New Mexico. April 1984 (Box 56)
  - Plays, Scenarios, Monologues, 1905-1941
    Unless otherwise indicated, plays are authored by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - The Spanish Main, with Alden Charles Noble. 1905 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Cellini of Florence. 1906 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Ryland, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman. 1912 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Original script in the handwriting of both authors.
    - Rembrandt. 1912 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Scenarios and notes for a play never completed.
    - Masque of the Four Schools, Carnegie Tech (fourth episode only). 1915 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Pennie Gay, with B. Iden Payne. 1921 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Three Plays for a Personality. 1922 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Shagreen. (2 copies belonging to Thomas Wood Stevens and John A. Willard). 1923 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Seven One-Act Plays. (Box 57, Folder 9)
      "Lucrezia Borgia," ca. 1906
      "Down and Out," 1907
      "Wireless Dispatch," 1907
      "Queen's Apothecary," 1908
      "Goya," 1910, with Kenneth Sawyer Goodman
      "Days of Salin," 1935
      "Drum Head," 1938
    - The Bolted Door, with Cora Hardy Jarrett. 1924 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Monologues. 1928-1929 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      "The Knitter"
      "Charlotte Corday"
      "Rachel"
      "Judith"
      "Marie Antoinette"